<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHY224</title>
    <link>http://phy224.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PHY224</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright, University of Toronto. 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://phy224.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://phy224.ca/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://phy224.ca/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Second Year Practicals are designed to extend the experimental skills you have acquired in your first year of study.
The course combines computational elements with lab exercises, aimed at developing your abilities to analyze experimental data and develop simple theoretical models of physical systems and phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>http://phy224.ca/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://phy224.ca/python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course you will use the Python language to analyze the data you collect, to plot figures and calculate physical quantities. This tutorial covers the basics of using Python, saving and loading data, and plotting data and fitting the data using &lt;code&gt;curve_fit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find alternate material on the Department of Physics &lt;a href=&#34;http://compwiki.physics.utoronto.ca/&#34;&gt;compwiki&lt;/a&gt; that covers many of the same topics but written by different people. In the 3rd and 4th year courses (e.g PHY407) you will use a textbook called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~mejn/computational-physics/&#34;&gt;Computational Physics with Python&lt;/a&gt;, and sample chapters introducing Python and the plotting libraries can be found at the author&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments and Wiring</title>
      <link>http://phy224.ca/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://phy224.ca/instruments/</guid>
      <description>After completing the Python exercises, you will do two single session labs to practice using laboratory instruments. One lab uses an oscilloscope and signal generator, the second lab uses multimeters, a DC power supply, and a resistor circuit.
   Title Location     The Oscilloscope MP235   The output resistance of a power supply MP222    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments</title>
      <link>http://phy224.ca/experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://phy224.ca/experiments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After completing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phy224.ca/python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; module and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phy224.ca/instruments&#34;&gt;Instruments and Wiring&lt;/a&gt; module, you will do a number of independent projects that include taking measurements using lab equipment, writing a Python program to fit or numerically solve a related equation, and maintaining  a record of your work in the lab book. The selected experiments are:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marking Scheme</title>
      <link>http://phy224.ca/markingscheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://phy224.ca/markingscheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://phy224.ca/pythonreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://phy224.ca/pythonreview/</guid>
      <description>import matplotlib as mpl %matplotlib inline mpl.rcParams[&amp;#39;savefig.dpi&amp;#39;]=300 #72 m Tutorial 1 Python is generally used as a scripting language : Scripts are files that contain programs and functions. Scripts interact with data files and other programs. A script file (here named script.py) can be run from the command line using the python command.
python script.py  Expressions and functions can also be called from an interactive interpreter launched by the python command without listing a script to run.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>